JULIUS NGETICH

PO. Box 04-20105 Nakuru, jlsngtch@gmail.com · 0701189354.

Portfolio Website· LinkedIn Profile GitHub

Visionary and result-driven IT professional with 2+ years of experience predominantly IT support and UX design. Strong aptitude for communication and customer relations with ability to identify and resolve issues, completing tasks ahead of schedule and managing multiple tasks. Recognized amongst peers for professionalism and being a pleasure to work with.

Success Examples:

- Managed a total of eight branches as an inventory manager and helped in bringing down cases of fraud and stock mismanagement which led to reduction in waste of items and increased sales and more accountability.
- Trained attachés on how to resolve technical issues as an IT technician.

EXPERIENCE

2023 TO PRESENT FREELANCER.

- Performing data entry tasks, data cleaning, visualization and transcription.
- Undertaking artificial intelligence task to aid in machine learning and development of smart applications and Internet of Things (IOT).
- Web and mobile application design.

2021 - 2022

PRESIDENTIAL DIGITALENT INTERN

INFORMATION & COMMUNICATION AUTHORITY, NAIROBI, KENYA

- Troubleshoot hardware and software issues including desktops, laptops and printers.
- Provide technical support to users including troubleshooting IT- related problems.
- Ensure security of IT systems including data backup and antivirus installation.
- Managed Asset Management System by updating it regularly with correct assets designation.
- Implemented IT Projects including system upgrades and installations.
- Managed and monitor network infrastructure including routers, switches, access points and VPN.
- Setting up links for virtual court sessions and managing Web conferences.

FEBRUARY 2021 – NOVEMBER 2021 INVENTORY MANAGER

JIRANI SMART MICROFINANCE, VOI, MOMBASA

- Conducting regular stock takes to determine available inventory.
- Studying sales numbers and forecasting future inventory needs.
- Using inventory management system to track down stock levels accurately.
- Collaborate with sales, purchase and other departments to ensure efficient flow of inventory.
- Receive and record new stock.

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2016

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS & COMPUTER SCIENCE.

MERU UNIVERSITY

- Distinguished member of university's Mathematics & Computer Science Society.
- Relevant Coursework: Advanced Computer Science & Applied Mathematics
- GPA: 3.00/3.59

SKILLS

- User Experience Design.
- Network Configuration.
- Information System.
- Web development.
- Relational Database Management System.
- Agile Project Management.
- Google Cloud Platform.
- HTML.

- Asset Management.
- Cyber Security.
- Python Programming.
- JavaScript programming.
- Java programming
- CSS.
- Wix/ WordPress.
- Ms. Office.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Google IT Automation with Python.
- Google UX Design.
- Prince 2 Agile Project Management.
- Software Development Skills.
- CCNA 1 -3 Completion letters.